<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>uncomfy - enshittification</title>
    <subtitle>uh... i have a website?</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://uncomfyhalomacro.pl/tags/enshittification/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://uncomfyhalomacro.pl"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://uncomfyhalomacro.pl/tags/enshittification/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>I will say this again &quot;Science is not the issue, intent is&quot;</title>
        <published>2024-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            Soc Virnyl Estela
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://uncomfyhalomacro.pl/blog/i-will-say-this-again-science-is-not-an-issue-intent-is/"/>
        <id>https://uncomfyhalomacro.pl/blog/i-will-say-this-again-science-is-not-an-issue-intent-is/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://uncomfyhalomacro.pl/blog/i-will-say-this-again-science-is-not-an-issue-intent-is/">&lt;p&gt;As a child, I was always into the field of science. Always curious, always
wanting to explore things to find an answer to all my questions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now as an adult, that intensity is now a small candle rather than a roaring
flame. It is not because I do not love science anymore. But it is because
of how the world changed a lot. Or to be more accurate, I have finally
noticed what the real world is like. Living as a child was living in a bliss
of ignorance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priorities change when you become an adult. Fortunately, science is always
progressing, and technology is always innovating and that brings excitement
or disappointment not because science and technology is a bad thing. But
because science can be also used for nefarious purposes. That&#x27;s not new.
I already know that. I am just not happy with the state of the world right now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my generation, of whom are born around the year 1990s and 2000s,
we have finally reached the peak of &lt;strong&gt;enshittification&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.  From our
internet and social networks, to the full-blown browser trackers
or spyware and advertisements that do not even make sense at all,
to the low-quality service and the not-stealing-stealing from many
subscription based media companies — we can see the world is now full of
nightmare-cocaine-fuel-dopamine-addicting-technology-to-false-science things.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
